[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[strange gurgling]
[奇怪的咕噜声]
[creature groaning, growling]
[生物呻吟，咆哮]
[hollering]
[喊叫]
Be quiet down there
or I'm calling the cops!
下面保持安静
不然我就报警了！
[both grunt]
both: What?
[两人咕哝]
两人：什么？
[sighs]
I said, be quiet
[叹气]
我说，安静点
or I'm calling the... [babbling]
或者我打电话给...[胡言乱语]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[loud crash]
[巨响]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Oh, my house.
哦，我的房子。
My shelter!
My life!
我的庇护所！
我的生活！
both: My, my, my.
两者：我的，我的，我的。
[grunts]
[both exclaim]
[咕哝]
[两人惊呼]
So, who you gonna stay with
那么，你要和谁呆在一起
till you find
a new house, Squidward?
直到你找到
新房子，章鱼哥？
Me or Patrick?
我还是帕特里克？
I wouldn't stay
with either of you two idiots
我不会留下来
和你们两个白痴中的任何一个
if the entire ocean was on fire
如果整个海洋都着火了
and you were the only ones
with water.
而你是唯一的人
用水。
- So there's a chance!
- Huh?
- 所以还有机会！
- 啊？
[growls]
[angry muttering]
[咆哮]
[愤怒的嘀咕]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[goofy babbling]
[胡言乱语]
[lonesome western music]
[孤独的西方音乐]
[water swishing]
[水哗哗]
[sighs]
Roughing it ain't so rough.
[叹气]
粗暴一点也没那么粗暴。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[thunder crashing]
[雷霆轰鸣]
Huh?
啊？
Too rough!
[sighs]
太粗暴了！
[叹气]
Oh, I guess it's Patrick.
哦，我猜是帕特里克。
[goofy grunting]
[愚蠢的咕哝]
[lighthearted music]
[轻松的音乐]
- [grunts]
- [hollers]
- [咕哝]
- [喊叫]
[grunts]
Identify myself!
[咕哝]
表明我自己的身份！
[grunts]
Patrick?
[咕哝]
帕特里克？
That is correct.
May I ask who's calling?
这是正确的。
请问你哪位？
Oh, hi, Squidward!
- [grunts]
哦，嗨，章鱼哥！
- [咕哝]
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
So, um, I've decided
to take you up
所以，嗯，我决定了
带你上去
on your generous invitation.
应您的慷慨邀请。
What about
my generator's vitamin?
怎么样
我的发电机的维生素？
Oh, good grief.
哦，真可惜。
I'm staying with you, you moron!
我会留在你身边，你这个白痴！
Um, that is, if you'll have me.
嗯，就是说，如果你愿意的话。
Oh, boy!
哦，孩子！
Squidward's staying over!
章鱼哥留下来了！
Sibley shining smine-mine!
- [grunting]
西布莉闪耀着我的光芒！
- [咕哝]
[laughing, babbling]
- [grunting]
[大笑，胡言乱语]
- [咕哝]
- Leedle-leedle-leedle-leedle!
- [sighs]
- 利德尔-利德尔-利德尔-利德尔！
- [叹气]
You can take my bed,
Squiddy, old buddy.
你可以占用我的床
鱿鱼，老伙计。
Well, um, maybe it won't be
so bad staying here after all.
嗯，嗯，也许不会
毕竟住在这里真是太糟糕了。
Sleep tight,
don't let the sand mites bite.
睡个好觉，
不要让沙螨叮咬。
But if they do, just let me
know and I'll smash 'em!
但如果他们这样做了，就让我
知道了我就会粉碎他们！
[sighs]
Um...
[叹气]
嗯...
[sniffs]
Huh.
[嗅嗅]
呵呵。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[slurps]
[啜饮]
Uh-huh.
[sighs]
嗯嗯。
[叹气]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Hmm.
[snoring]
唔。
[打鼾]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[stammers]
What?
[结巴]
什么？
Oh, a leaky rock?
噢，一块漏水的石头？
[snoring]
[打鼾]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[air whistling]
[空气呼啸]
Oh, you titanic twit,
get down from there!
哦，你这个泰坦尼克号笨蛋，
从那里下来！
[gasps] I'll smash them
for you, Squidward!
[喘气]我会粉碎他们
为了你，章鱼哥！
[hollers]
[喊叫]
Squidward?
Where are you?
章鱼哥？
你在哪里？
In your navel.
在你的肚脐里。
- [grunting]
- [gasps]
- [咕哝]
- [喘气]
[laughs]
That tickles.
[笑]
那很痒。
[rooster crows]
[公鸡打鸣]
[grunts, yawns]
[咕噜声，哈欠]
Hmm?
What is this place?
唔？
这是什么地方？
[exclaims, sniffs]
[惊呼，嗅嗅]
[gasps]
Huh?
[喘气]
啊？
[sniffing, babbling]
[嗅嗅，胡言乱语]
Squidward, did you do all this?
章鱼哥，这一切都是你做的吗？
Well, I figured
if I have to stay here,
嗯，我想
如果我必须留在这里
I might as well make it livable.
我不妨让它变得宜居。
Lard cake?
猪油蛋糕？
If you make me lard cakes
every morning, Squiddy,
如果你给我做猪油蛋糕
每天早上，鱿鱼，
you can do anything you want.
你可以做任何你想做的事。
[groans]
- Ah-ah-ah-ah.
[呻吟]
- 啊啊啊啊。
The etiquette spoon says,
"Eat like a gentleman."
礼仪勺说，
“吃得像个绅士。”
Ah, a gentleman.
啊，一位绅士。
[grunts, sighs]
[咕哝，叹气]
Watch me, idiot.
看着我，白痴。
A gentleman eats like this.
君子就是这样吃的。
[goofy exclamations]
[愚蠢的感叹]
Holy halibut,
can he actually be taught?
圣大比目鱼，
他真的可以被教导吗？
I can mold him.
我可以塑造他。
I can squeeze this lump of clay
我可以挤压这块粘土
into a cultured sophisticate.
变成有文化的世故。
I will make you
the most tolerable roommate
我会让你
最能容忍的室友
of all time!
有史以来！
You'll be my
"roommate-sterpiece!"
你将是我的
“室友的杰作！”
Oh, more lard cakes, please!
哦，请再来一份猪油蛋糕！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- [grunts]
- [exclaims]
- [咕哝]
- [惊呼]
[chuckles]
[笑声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
- [sighs]
- Huh?
- [叹气]
- 啊？
- Oh!
- [grunts]
- 哦！
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
- [exclaims]
[笑]
- [惊呼]
[playing scales]
[演奏音阶]
[gasps]
[playing discordant scales]
[喘气]
[演奏不和谐音阶]
[playing mellow tune]
[演奏柔和的曲子]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[plays discordant note]
[演奏不和谐的音符]
Oh![grunts]
哦！[咕哝]
[lighthearted music]
[轻松的音乐]
Hmm.
唔。
[gasps]
Aha!
[喘气]
啊哈！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[blows kiss, sighs]
[飞吻，叹息]
- [blows kiss]
- [chuckles]
- [飞吻]
- [轻笑]
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[all chattering]
[大家都在喋喋不休]
[both playing rousing tune]
[两人都演奏着振奋人心的曲子]
Culture lovers,
文化爱好者，
welcome to the Classy Kiosk!
欢迎来到优雅的信息亭！
I am Squid-tacular,
我是乌贼，
and this is my protégé,
Patrick Panache.
这是我的门徒，
帕特里克·帕纳奇.
He taught me everything I blow!
我吹的一切都是他教的！
[plays discordant note]
[演奏不和谐的音符]
And now, get ready to...
现在，准备好...
both: Feel the art!
两者：感受艺术！
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[sighs]
[grunting]
[叹气]
[咕噜声]
Yes...
[muttering inaudibly]
是的...
[小声嘀咕]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[crowd booing]
[人群嘘声]
[babbling]
[all gasp]
[胡言乱语]
[全都喘气]
[all chattering, cheering]
[大家叽叽喳喳，欢呼雀跃]
♪ ♪
♪♪
What?
什么？
Hey, watch me, everyone!
嘿嘿，大家看着我！
I will now bedazzle
your dazzlers
我现在会眼花缭乱
你的眼花缭乱
with interpretative dance!
与诠释舞蹈！
[babbling]
[胡说]
[crowd grumbling]
[人群抱怨声]
[lighthearted jazzy music]
[轻松的爵士音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[grunts]
- My turn!
[咕哝]
- 轮到我了！
[babbling]
[胡说]
[lively orchestral music]
[活泼的管弦乐]
[all gasp, cheering]
[全场喘气，欢呼]
What the...
什么...
Who knew that Patrick
could dance like an angel?
谁知道帕特里克
可以像天使一样跳舞吗？
[laughs]
Bravo, bravo!
[笑]
太棒了，太棒了！
Oh, Mr. Krabs,
you dropped this.
哦，蟹老板，
你把这个掉了。
Oop, thanks.[laughs]
噢，谢谢。[笑]
Patrick Panache!
帕特里克·帕纳奇！
You make a better Squidward
than Squidward does.
你会成为更好的章鱼哥
比章鱼哥还多。
[laughs]
[笑]
[imitating Squidward]
I do?
【模仿章鱼哥】
我愿意吗？
- Huh?
- [laughs]
- 啊？
- [笑]
[sighs]
[laughter]
[叹气]
[笑声]
Hey, stop making those noises!
嘿，别再发出那些声音了！
Those are my noises![sighs]
这些是我的声音！[叹气]
- [sighs]
- Huh?
- [叹气]
- 啊？
- [laughs]
- [growls]
- [笑]
- [咆哮]
- [laughs]
- [growls]
- [笑]
- [咆哮]
- [laughs]
- Hey-hey!
- [笑]
- 嘿嘿！
Patrick is the best Squidward!
all: Huzzah!
帕特里克是最好的章鱼哥！
全体：万岁！
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
So, Squidward, what do you think
那么，章鱼哥，你觉得怎么样？
of your new protégé, huh?
你的新门生，是吧？
New protégé...
[growling]
新门生...
[咆哮]
He stinks!
他很臭！
And he's not a better me!
而他也不是更好的我！
He's an imposter.
- Hmm.
他是个冒名顶替者。
- 唔。
Well, if Patrick makes
a better Squidward,
好吧，如果帕特里克让
更好的章鱼哥，
maybe you'd make
a better Patrick.
也许你会做
一个更好的帕特里克。
[laughs]
- [scoffs]
[笑]
- [嘲笑]
Yeah, right, "I would make
a better Patrick."
是的，没错，“我会让
一个更好的帕特里克。”
[stammers]
Wait a minute, that's it!
[结巴]
等一下，就是这样！
That'll teach him.
Oh, thanks, SpongeBob.
那会教他的。
哦，谢谢，海绵宝宝。
- Mm.
- [smooches]
- 毫米。
- [亲吻]
Oh, wait a minute, Squidward,
you dropped your chee...
噢，等一下，章鱼哥，
你掉了你的奶酪...
[sniffs, gags]
[groans]
[嗅嗅，堵嘴]
[呻吟]
[groans, sighs]
[呻吟，叹息]
Well, Patrick,
time for another lovely day
好吧，帕特里克，
又是美好一天的时间
in the flower garden of life.
在生命的花园里。
[sighs]
- [babbling]
[叹气]
- [胡言乱语]
I love you, brick.[grunts]
我爱你，砖头。[咕哝]
I love you, brick.
[grunts]
我爱你，砖头。
[咕哝]
I love you, brick.[grunts]
我爱你，砖头。[咕哝]
Squidward, you kelp head,
章鱼哥，你这个海藻头，
what did you do
to my beautiful house?
你做了什么
去我美丽的房子吗？
Define "do."
定义“做”。
[grunts]
- [hollers]
[咕哝]
- [喊叫]
Don't put my art up your nose,
you cretin!
别把我的艺术放在你的鼻子底下
你这个白痴！
[babbles]
[胡言乱语]
[gulps]
I might need that someday.
[吞咽]
有一天我可能需要它。
Duh...
- [sighs]
呃……
- [叹气]
I'll play
the old licorice stick.
我会玩
老甘草棒
That always soothes my nerves.
这总是能舒缓我的神经。
[yelps]
- [munching]
[尖叫声]
- [咀嚼]
Doesn't taste like licorice.
味道不像甘草。
My clarinet!
我的单簧管！
No!
不！
[spits]
Oh, sorry, you want some?
[吐口水]
哦，抱歉，你想要一些吗？
Ah-ah-ah!
啊啊啊！
The etiquette spoon came back
礼仪勺回来了
and he says,
"Eat like a gentlemen."
他说，
“像绅士一样吃饭。”
- [goofy babbling]
- [laughing]
- [愚蠢的胡言乱语]
- [笑]
Um... um, I'm going to go play
嗯……嗯，我去玩了
with my best friend SpongeBob.
和我最好的朋友海绵宝宝。
[laughing]
[笑]
Yeah, you do that
是的，你这样做
while I take a Pat nap.
当我小睡时。
[sighs]
[叹气]
[grunts]
[both laughing]
[咕哝]
[两人都笑了]
[grunts] What are those ninnies
up to now?
[咕噜声]那些傻瓜是什么？
到现在为止？
[laughs] I told you
[笑]我告诉过你了
you'd make a
great Patrick, Squidward!
你会做一个
伟大的帕特里克、章鱼哥！
[laughing]
[笑]
Pipe down, you two!
你们两个，冷静下来！
Hey, Patrick, heads up!
嘿，帕特里克，抬头！
[grunts]
- Ooh!
[咕哝]
- 哦！
both: Bull's-eye!
[both laughing]
双方：靶心！
[两人都笑了]
I said be quiet, you two,
or I'm calling the...
我说你们两个安静一点
或者我打电话给...
[gulps]
Mud.
[吞咽]
泥。
Puddle!
水坑！
[grunts, babbles]
[咕哝声，胡言乱语]
[gasps, sighs]
[喘气，叹气]
[laughs]
Hey!
[笑]
嘿！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[spits]
He's Patrick again!
[吐口水]
他又是帕特里克了！
Finally!
最后！
both: Squidward, look!
两人：章鱼哥，看！
[goofy babbling]
[胡言乱语]
It's the new house I ordered!
这就是我订的新房！
No more Patrick!
不再有帕特里克了！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
all: Yay!
全体：耶！
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
[all groan, grunt]
[所有呻吟声、咕噜声]
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
[groans]
[呻吟]
both: Whoo!
- [laughs]
两人：哇！
- [笑]
- Good-night, SpongeBob.
- Night, Patrick.
- 晚安，海绵宝宝。
- 晚安，帕特里克。
both: Good-night, Squidward.
两人：晚安，章鱼哥。
[both smooch]
[双方接吻]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]